Welcome to the new feature introduction video of Marvelous Designer 2025.
In the 2025 version, you can experience the latest module library to improve your work efficiency.
In the window options in the main menu, you can choose to display or hide the module library window.
The module editor and module editor in the previous version have been integrated into the module library.
As in the previous version, click the small arrow in the upper right corner to choose to fold or display the module library window.
In the previous version, the module components were defined in the module editor.
Then go to the module editor to use it.
Now you can directly define the module components in the module library.
The module library structure order is the group type style component.
The current structure order is very convenient for the management and integration of these design components.
If you need to define certain versions of the 3D window as components, you need to follow the structure from the group to find the corresponding style type.
Now we will explain the module library structure from the outside to the inside.
The outer layer is the group.
You can choose a group to add styles.
Or click the add button in the upper right corner to choose the group to add.
Choose the folder to store the group files.
Then the category and style of the subordinates will be stored in this folder.
Click the right arrow on the group file folder.
You can choose to copy the file folder path or delete the file folder.
You can click the refresh button to refresh the group list.
In this tutorial, we will choose the male group.
When you double click a group,
it will display the categories below the group.
In the upper left corner, you can see the structure of the current folder.
Click the group name to go back to the group list.
You can use the existing category or click the add button.
Choose to add a category.
Add a clothing category.
Click the refresh button to refresh the category folder.
However, only the folder that contains the component module will be displayed in the module library.
In the category folder, click the right arrow.
You can choose to copy the folder path or delete the file folder.
In this tutorial, we will choose the Basic Shirts category.
When you double click the category folder,
it will display all the categories below the category.
Now, we will add the original half-sleeved T-shirt in the default asset library as an example to define the style.
Click the add button in the upper right corner.
Choose the add style menu.
In the pop-up window, enter the name and set the shortcut.
The app will default to use the fashion shortcut in the 3D window as the shortcut.
Then click OK.
If you want to use other pictures as shortcuts,
you can click the icon on the camera and then go to the folder.
You can click the icon mode to switch the display mode to preview or list type.
Click the refresh button to refresh the style list.
Click the right arrow on the style shortcut.
Click the edit style menu.
You can adjust the style shortcut or name.
You can also delete the style type by deleting the options.
Click the add button in the upper right corner.
You can choose to assign the style to the product line.
After selecting this option,
you will add a new product line file to the top of the style under the category.
You can expand these styles.
In the top right corner of the product line list,
click the add product line option.
In the pop-up window, set the name and shortcut of the new product line.
You can also choose to add a new product line to the same style,
and then copy the selected product line.
Add a new product line to it.
The name and shortcut can also be adjusted.
Double-click to open the product line.
You can see the style type below.
Now let's select a clothing type first.
Then select a style type.
Here I choose a men's top.
Then select the low-brow embroidery style.
After opening, you can see the component modules of each part under the selected style.
Double-click on other styles.
You can switch to other styles under the same type.
You can see the components of the front, back, sleeves, and collar here.
Each type of component has multiple components to change.
It is the same as the previous modular configuration.
The double-click module component will be added to the component.
If there is a component, it will switch to the selected component.
Each part of the clothing is called a component.
For example, in T-shirt, the components are the front, back, sleeves, and collar.
After setting the component type,
you can define the clothing version in the 3D window
and define it as a variety of components.
Now let's learn how to add a component type without a component structure.
Click on the Add button in the upper right corner to open the Add menu.
Select Add component type.
You can set the new component type in the pop-up window.
The top type is the clothing location of the component.
The bottom is the type label to set them.
In the default situation, the label and the selected component type are the same.
You can also modify it according to your needs.
If you want to do different styles or types of design for the same part,
you can use the labels.
Their classification is very useful.
You can choose to save the component configuration in the upper right corner.
After saving the component configuration,
these component types will be saved as configuration files.
Next time you open it, you can call this component structure.
Select Open component configuration option.
You can open the previously saved configuration.
Later, we will learn how to use the automatic module fastening label function.
Click on the Add button in the upper right corner to open the new component list.
When all component types are set,
you can start adding components for each type.
Click on the Add new component button in the upper right corner of the component type.
The module generator window will appear.
In the window pop-up,
a module type will be displayed in the list.
Here you can manage the components under each type.
In the upper right corner, you can choose to edit the module type and configuration.
In the module edit area,
you can save, edit or delete these module components.
Using the automatic module fastening label option,
you can quickly separate the modules into each component type.
After selecting the option,
you will see that each module automatically changes its color
to distinguish its component type.
You can refer to the name and color
to determine whether these modules are correctly matched to the type of component.
If the modules are correctly matched to the component type,
click on the save button on the right side of the camera icon.
You can save the module.
When the module is correctly saved,
the hook icon on the left side will light up,
which means that the module has been activated.
If the automatic module fastening function is not working correctly,
you can click on the marker icon
to manually select the module type.
You can click on the module type
or click on the shift key to select multiple modules.
Then press the enter key to confirm the selection.
When all the module types are correctly saved,
the add button on the bottom will activate.
After clicking on the add button,
a spring will pop up.
Click on the prompt operation
to check whether the sewing line structure between the modules is correct.
Click on the sewing line.
You will see the marking on the sewing line.
The prompt is the label of the module component on both sides of the sewing line.
If the sewing line is wrong,
please click on the cancel button
to manually adjust the sewing line
and try again.
After confirming the sewing line,
click on the confirm key to confirm the definition of the module.
Then adjust the clothing panel
and re-register an additional module.
Click on the add new module button
in the upper right corner of the module type.
The window of the 2D panel
will switch to the mode of selecting panels.
Follow the mouse button to select the panels in the window of 2D.
Click on the shift key to select the panels.
Click on the enter key to confirm the selection of panels.
Then, edit the shrink chart and name.
As the new modules increase,
you can switch them in the module library.
After switching the modules,
the automatically detect the matching between the modules
and return the sewing line.
Click on the right button on the module.
You can select the corresponding option in the menu.
Delete the selected module and delete this module.
Share the selected module.
Share the selected module
to other models under the same category.
Change the shrink chart and replace the shrink chart of the module.
Use the new module to replace it.
Change this module to a newly defined module.
Finally, let's look at the related settings
of the module in the user's self-definition.
Go to the main menu.
Set the user's self-definition.
Find other options.
Protect module optimization by limiting editing.
When this option is selected,
add, edit, delete and automatic module optimization labels
will no longer be usable.
Reduce the number of modules and limit editing.
Prohibit a mixture of modules of different styles.
After opening the module,
you can't mix different modules
and make them into one set of clothing.
When you add a module from a different style,
a warning window will pop up.
If necessary,
you can click the window button and select and verify.
Thank you.